<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- Copyright 2024 proletarius101 -->
<component type="desktop-application">
    <id>me.proton.Pass</id>

    <name>Proton Pass</name>
    <summary>Encrypted password manager to keep your login credentials safe</summary>

    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
    <developer id="ch.protonmail">
        <name>Proton AG</name>
    </developer>
    <project_group>Proton</project_group>

    <description>
        <p>**This is a community package of Proton Pass and is not officially supported by Proton AG.**</p>

        <p>Get the password manager created by the scientists who met at CERN behind Proton Mail,
            the world's largest encrypted email provider. Proton Pass is open source, end-to-end
            encrypted, and protected by Swiss privacy laws.</p>

        <p>Pass offers more than other free password managers and has no ads or data collection. You
            can use it for free forever on all your devices to create and store unlimited passwords,
            autofill logins, generate 2FA codes, create email aliases, secure your notes, and
            more.</p>

        <p>How can Proton Pass be free forever?</p>
        <p>We offer Pass for free because everyone deserves online privacy and security. This is
            possible thanks to our supportive community on paid plans. If you would like to support
            our work and get access to premium features, consider upgrading your plan.</p>

        <p>Protect more than just your passwords.</p>
        <p>Join over 100 million people who have signed up for Proton's privacy ecosystem, which
            includes Proton Mail, Proton Drive, Proton Calendar, Proton VPN, and more. Take back
            control of your privacy online with our encrypted email, calendar, file storage, and
            VPN.</p>

        <p>Protect your logins and their metadata with battle-tested end-to-end encryption</p>
        <p>While many other password managers only encrypt your password, Proton Pass uses
            end-to-end encryption on all your stored login details (including your username, the
            website address, and more). Pass protects your information with the same battle-tested
            encryption libraries all Proton services use.</p>

        <p>Audit Pass's open-source code</p>
        <p>Like all other Proton services, Pass is open source and built on the principle of trust
            through transparency. As scientists, we know that transparency and peer review lead to
            better security. All Proton Pass apps are open source, meaning anyone can verify our
            security claims for themselves.</p>

        <p>With Proton Pass, you can:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Store and auto-sync unlimited logins on unlimited devices: You can create, store,
                and manage your credentials from anywhere with our browser extensions and apps for
                Android and iPhone/iPad.</li>
            <li>Sign in faster with Proton Pass autofill: You no longer need to copy and paste your
                username and password. Easily and securely log in with Proton Pass autofill
                technology.</li>
            <li>Avoid weak passwords: With our built-in secure password generator, you can easily
                generate strong, unique, and random passwords based on the security requirements for
                every website you sign up to.</li>
            <li>Safely store encrypted notes: You can save private notes in Pass and access them on
                all your devices.</li>
            <li>Protect Proton Pass with biometric login access: You can add an extra layer of
                protection to Proton Pass by using your fingerprint or face to unlock the app.</li>
            <li>Create unique email addresses with hide-my-email aliases: Proton Pass helps you hide
                your personal email address with email aliases. Keep spam out of your inbox, avoid
                being tracked everywhere, and protect yourself from data breaches.</li>
            <li>Make 2FA easy with our built-in authenticator: With Pass's integrated 2FA
                authenticator, using 2FA is finally fast and convenient. Easily add a 2FA code for
                any website and autofill it when you log in.</li>
            <li>Easily organize and share your sensitive data with vaults: Manage your logins,
                secure notes, and email aliases with vaults. Share individual items or an entire
                vault with your family, friends, or colleagues.</li>
            <li>Quick offline access to your login data: Access your stored passwords and notes in
                Pass from wherever you are, even when your phone has no internet connection.</li>
            <li>Secure your Pass account with additional security measures: Protect all your data
                with another layer of protection, either with TOTP or U2F/FIDO2 security keys.</li>
            <li>Get unlimited email forwards: There's no limit on the number of emails you can have
                forwarded from your alias to your inbox.</li>
        </ul>
    </description>

    <url type="homepage">https://proton.me/pass</url>
    <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/ProtonMail/WebClients</url>
    <url
        type="contact">https://proton.me/support/troubleshooting?product=pass</url>
    <url type="help">https://proton.me/support/pass</url>
    <url type="translate">https://proton.me/blog/translation-community</url>

    <launchable type="desktop-id">me.proton.Pass.desktop</launchable>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default" xml:lang="en">
            <image>https://pmecdn.protonweb.com/image-transformation/?s=s&amp;image=cta_keep_your_passwords_safe_for_free_4f90956465.png</image>
            <caption
                xml:lang="en">The interface showcases user-friendly access to your Netflix credentials, complete with OTP generation for added security.</caption>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>

    <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
        <content_attribute id="money-purchasing">intense</content_attribute>
    </content_rating>

    <releases>
        <release version="1.36.0" date="2026-04-03">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Custom item fields are now searchable</li>
                    <li>Hide biometrics unlock option on Linux</li>
                    <li>Lock desktop app when closed</li>
                    <li>Improve importers</li>
                    <li>Group sharing</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.35.0" date="2026-03-09">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Support for B2B groups</li>
                    <li>Fix an issue on invites when users have many addresses</li>
                    <li>New beta channel for desktop apps</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.34.2" date="2026-01-30">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Allow Pass Plus Trial to access all paid features</li>
                    <li>Fix minor Pass Plus Trial UI issues</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="1.33.5" date="2026-01-14">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.33.4" date="2026-01-07">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.33.3" date="2025-12-18">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.33.2" date="2025-12-17">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.33.0" date="2025-11-21">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.32.11" date="2025-10-27">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.32.10" date="2025-10-14">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.32.7" date="2025-09-18">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.32.6" date="2025-09-09">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.32.3" date="2025-07-30">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.32.2" date="2025-07-01">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.32.0" date="2025-06-24">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.31.5" date="2025-06-04">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.31.4" date="2025-05-19">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.31.3" date="2025-05-14">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.31.2" date="2025-05-12">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.31.1" date="2025-04-15">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.31.0" date="2025-04-08">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.30.1" date="2025-03-24">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.29.8" date="2025-03-07">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.29.5" date="2025-03-03">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.29.3" date="2025-02-17">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.29.2" date="2025-02-07">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.29.1" date="2025-02-04">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.29.0" date="2025-01-28">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.28.0" date="2025-01-21">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.27.2" date="2025-01-06">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.27.0" date="2024-12-20">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.26.0" date="2024-12-09">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.25.0" date="2024-11-25">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.24.4" date="2024-11-13">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.24.3" date="2024-11-11">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.24.1" date="2024-10-31">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.23.1" date="2024-10-07">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.23.0" date="2024-09-20">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.22.2" date="2024-08-26">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.22.1" date="2024-08-20">
            <description />
        </release>
        <release version="1.22.0" date="2024-08-06" />
        <release version="1.16.1" date="2024-03-21" />
    </releases>
</component>
